THAMAL WIJETUNGE

Markham, Ontario, L6B 0Y6 647 838 2223 · thamaltw97@outlook.com https://linkedin.com/in/thamaltw97/ · thamaltw97.github.io/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a confident, proactive, and friendly software enthusiastic person with 3 years experience in the software field. I carryout extensive software development knowledge in a variety of areas. Positive approach and problem solving are my biggest assets. With exceptional planning, execution, and interpersonal skills, I am a hardworking, innovative, and self-motivated team player.

SKILLS

- Technologies:
 - Frontend & Backend: JavaScript, C#,
 ASP.Net, ReactJS, NodeJS, Java, C, Android,
 Python, and other similar technologies.
 - O Database: SQL, Oracle (PL/SQL), MongoDB
 - O Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, SVN
 - Testing: JIRA
- Hands-on-experience with all phases of Software Development Life Cycle.

- Functional and integration testing.
- Ability to work independently as well as in a team environment.
- Software implementation and testing.
- Database management.
- Good communication skills.
- Good leadership skills.

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2022 – DECEMBER 2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DP INFOTECH (PVT) LTD, SRI LANKA

- Completion of the Pearl Bay system with ERP and POS system for the David Pieris water park using ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS & MongoDB.
- Implemented Management Accounts module into the current ERP system of David Pieris Group using JavaScript with jQuery, .NET Core & Oracle database.

OCTOBER 2020 – AUGUST 2022

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DP INFOTECH (PVT) LTD, SRI LANKA

- Full design and implementation of Pearl Bay system with ERP and POS system for the David Pieris water park using ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS & MongoDB.
- Drafted software requirements and managed software design and implementation.
- Developed, coordinated, and conducted complex tests and debugged the systems.
- Managed software throughout SDLC and collaborated with team members to address issues.
- Defined and continuously improved UI development best practices.
- Implemented Workshop module into the current ERP system of David Pieris Group using JavaScript with jQuery, .NET Core & Oracle database.

NOVEMBER 2019 – SEPTEMBER 2020

TRAINEE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, DP INFOTECH (PVT) LTD, SRI LANKA

- Implemented new modules (Imports, Technical) into the current ERP system of David Pieris Group using JavaScript with jQuery, .NET Core & Oracle database.
- Managed software throughout SDLC and collaborated with team members to address issues.
- Gained knowledge in ERP level systems, Oracle database development and web development.

EDUCATION

FROM JANUARY 2023 ONWARDS

ONTARIO COLLEGE GRADUATE CERTIFICATE IN COMPUTER SOFTWARE AND DATABASE DEVELOPMENT

LOYALIST COLLEGE IN TORONTO-VICTORIA PARK CAMPUS, ONTARIO

JUNE 2017 - JULY 2021

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (HONOURS) IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIZED IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

SRI LANKA INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, SRI LANKA

Some Projects involved.

- 4th year research project on Intelligent system for agriculture in Sri Lanka, using Android with Java and Python for machine learning with TensorFlow lite.
- 3rd year web project on implementing an e-commerce site using ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS and MongoDB with rest services.
- 3rd year stand-alone project on a code complexity measurement tool to measure the complexity of any C++ or Java code, using Java.
- 3rd year mobile application development project on a current mobile banking app (ComBank) to improve the UI/UX, using Java in android studio.
- 2nd year IT project on a complete POS system for textile showroom client, using Java, SQL in NetBeans with MySQL workbench and MySQL query browser.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Currently following: AWS Certified Developer Associate
- Certificate of completion: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure Trainocate

REFERENCES

Available upon request.